An Annotated Calendar of the Letters of Charles Darwin in the Library of the American Philosophical Society 1799-1882 Mss.B.D25
American Philosophical Society
- Calendar of Letters
  - To [George John] ROMANES; no location, [1876 ca. June 15]; 495; A postscript, S by init.; 9 x7.25 4p., sketch
    2. See Francis Darwin, "On the Protrusion of Protoplasmic Filaments from the Glandular Hairs of the Common Teasel (Dipsacus sylvestris)," Proc. R. Soc., 26 (1877): 4-8.
    3. CD is joking about Romanes's interest in spiritualism; see Life of Romanes, 48-49.
    4. "On the Glandular Bodies on Acacia sphaerocephala and Cecropia peltata Serving as Food for Ants...," J. Linn. Soc. (Botany), 15 (1875-1877): 398-409.
    5. See Richardson, "Abstract Report to `Nature' on Experimentation on Animals for the Advance of Practical Medicine," Nature, Lond., 14 (1876): 149-52, 170-72, 197-99, 250-52, 289-91, 339-41, and 369-72. Published in the issue for June 15, 1876, and subsequent issues.
  - To?; Down (type 8), [?1876] June 30th; 496; ALS; 8 x5; 1p.
    Has not heard of essay mentioned by corr.; would like copy if it is small and corr. has a spare one; will not answer it, as this takes time.
  - To [George Warde or Ebenezer] NORMAN; Down (type 8) ALFRED M.?, [1876] Sept. 15th [end. 1876/ 15 Septr.]; 497; ALS; 8 x5; 2p. and end. [1876/ 15 Septr./ Chas. Darwin/ on receipt/ of letter of/ condolence, for/ death of Daughter/ in Law--]
    Thanks for note; it has been a terrible blow; [Amy Richenda Ruck Darwin] was sweet and gentle; son [Francis Darwin] has gone to North Wales where she was buried yesterday.
  - To [Peter Martin DUNCAN]; Down (type 8), 1876 Sep. 19; 498; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    While cleaning out a room, found a fossil coral and a long MS. account of it by [William] Lonsdale; these must have arrived while CD was ill, and they were forgotten; will send them to corr.
  - To [?William] MARSHALL; Down (type 8), 1876 Sep. 19; 499; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Wishes to build a billiard room, with bedroom and dressing room above; wants corr. to undertake the project; come to Down; Horace [Darwin] does not know corr.'s London address; must hurry with project because winter is coming.
  - To [?William] MARSHALL; Down (type 8), [1876]; 500; ALS; 8 x5; 1p.
    Please write to "Mr. Laslett/ Builder/ Farnborough/ Kent." and arrange to meet him at Down House on Tuesday; leaves home [for Leith Hill Place] on Wednesday [October 4], so cannot invite corr. to sleep at Down. 1
    1. See preceding letter, above, for year. For departure to Leith Hill, see "Darwin's Journal," 20. Laslett may have been William Emerson Laslett the solicitor.
  - To [?William] MARSHALL; Down (type 8), [1876]; 501; ALS; 8 x5; 6p.
    Accepts Mr. Deards's estimate for the work, as his is cheaper; repay Laslett and [?Thomas Hayter] Lewis for expenses involved in estimates; make trap door to roof out of glass, and put flooring in attic crawl space, so lumber may be stored there; forget Horace [Darwin]'s idea about partition; wants to enlarge window in present hall; wants sealed airspace inside the outer walls.
    1. See preceding letter, above, for date.
  - To W[illiam Erasmus DARWIN]; no location (blue paper), [1876]; 502; AL, S by init.; 8 x5; 2p. (enclosure wanting)
    Send enclosed to Capt. [?James Felix or?Henry M.] Jones; proofs will reach corr. soon; new chapter seven will have to be much corrected by CD; 1 does not think much of [Edward Drinker] Cope's essay ["On the Origin of Genera," Proc. Acad. nat. Sci. Philad., 20 (1868): 242-300], read long ago when received; "He writes very obscurely, but is an excellent Naturalist. He looks, following [Jean Louis Rodolphe] Agassiz at a genus as something essentially distinct from a species, which I believe to be quite an error."
    1. CD here refers to Fertilisation of Orchids (1877), which he was readying for publication in 1876. Thus the year for this letter. On the new chapter seven, see page vi of the book.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877] 1876; 503; LS; 28 x5; 3p.
    Is pleased to propose corr. for Royal Society; will be at 2 Bryanston Street in London on the 6th; will sign certificate then; suggest others, not on the council [of the Royal Society], who might also sign it; [John Scott] Burdon-Sanderson should sign it; is reading corr.'s medusa paper; 3 will call on corr. early next week.
    1. CD's amanuensis apparently wrote the wrong year. See subsequent letter, below, and check "Darwin's Journal," 20, to see that CD went to London of January 6, 1877, but not on January 6, 1876.
    2. Francis Darwin, CD's amanuensis, penned a short note at end of letter.
    3. "Further Observations on the Locomotor System of Medusae," Phil. Trans. R. Soc., 167 (1877): 659-752.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), 1877 Jan. 4.; 504; LS; 8 x5; 1p.
    From what corr. says, CD will not send certificate [proposing corr. for Royal Society]; will bring blank certificate to London; invites corr. to lunch at 2 Bryanston Street on Monday [January 8]; bring or send certificate.
  - To Howard MILLER; Down (type 8), 1877 Jan. 10th [pmk. JA 10/ 77]; 505; ALS; 8 x5; 1p. and env., add. [Howard Miller Esqr/ Elderton/ Armstrong Co./ Pa./ U. States]
    Thanks for offer, which would be of value to anyone engaged in embryological studies, but CD is not so engaged.
  - To R[?ichar]d [KE.?]; Down (type 8) 1, 1877 Feb. 15th-- [end. Feb. 16/ 77]; 506; ALS; 8 x5; 2p., end. [Books sent & advised/ Feb. 16/ 77 Rd Ke.]
    Please send Botanische Zeitung for 1857; send [Eugene] Michalet, ["Sur la Floraison des Viola de la Section Nomimium, de l' Oxalis acetosella et du Linaria spuria,"] Bull. Soc. bot. Fr., 7 [(1860):] 465[-70]; and send [Joseph] Duval-Jouve, ["Note sur Quelques Plantes Critiques du Flora monspeliensis de Linné,"] Bull. Soc. bot. Fr., 10 [(1863); 10-20]; send also H[enri Ernest] Baillon, "Sur l'Émission des Tubes Polliniques des Helianthemum," [ Adansonia, Recueil Périodique d'Observations Botaniques, 2 (1861):] 56[-59]; send by rail.
    1. Lower half of this printed address is highlighted with a drawn hand pointing to it.
  - To Miss JACOBSON; Down (type 8), 1877 Feb. 25th; 507; AL in third person S; 6 x5; 1p.
    CD accedes to corr.'s request.
  - To [George Henry Kendrick] THWAITES; Down (type 8), 1877 Mar 26; 508; LS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Thanks for specimens; sexual differences remind CD of complemental males in cirripedes; hopes [John Obadiah] Westwood will make a paper on subject; 1 wonders if specimens play role in fertilization of figs, a subject studied by Dr [Hermann] Crüger in West Indies; has seen account of corr. from Miss [Marianne] North; 2 has just examined Oxalis sensitiva specimen sent long ago, and to CD's surprise its flowers are trimorphic and cleistogamic. 3
    1. "Descriptions of the Insects Infesting the Seeds of Ficus Sycomorus and Carica," Trans. R. ent. Soc. Lond., 30 (1882): 47-60.
    2. See entry for North in DNB; she was in Ceylon in 1876.
    3. See Darwin, Different Forms of Flowers (1877), 322-24.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877]; 509; ALS; 8 x5; 5p.
    Is astonished that corr. was not on list [of newly-elected Fellows of Royal Society]; [Joseph Dalton Hooker], President [of the Royal Society] and others implied that age and position in scientific society (e.g. being a professor) weighed heavily, as did having been proposed many times; youth is a disqualification; Council [of Royal Society] acts honestly; corr.'s work is valuable; connot remember names of fifteen [new Fellows]; 2 do not withdraw name; offers to re-propose corr. for election.
    1. See letters to Romanes dated January 2 and January 4, 1877, above.
    2. For names, see Proc. R. Soc., 26 (1877): 210.
  - To Otto ZACHARIAS; Down (type 8), 1877 April 26th; 510; ALS; 8 x5; 3p. and env., add. [Dr. Otto Zacharias/ Red: der Nordsee-Zeitung/ Geestemünde/ Germany]
    Thanks for anomalous foot of the pig, but CD is not osteologist enough to pass judgment on it; is away from home; will send foot to Prof. [William Henry] Flower at Royal College of Surgeons, who has studied limbs of Ungulata and who is "a most careful & admirable observer"; will send notice if any "remarkable peculiarities" are found.
  - From W[illiam] H[enry] FLOWER; Royal College of Surgeons of England./ Lincoln's Inn. Fields,/ (W.C.), 1877 May 3; 511; ALS 7.25 x4.5 4p.
    Thanks for pig's foot; it contains an extra digit, which may be either a reversion or a case of over-development; wants further information about other feet of affected pig and about feet of pig's relatives. 1
  - From W[illiam] H[enry] FLOWER; Royal College of Surgeons of England./ Lincoln's Inn Fields,/ (W.C.), 1877 May 17th; 512; ALS; 7.25 x4.5 3p., sketch
    Thanks for information about pig's foot in letter of May 10; sends catalog of their teratological series; mentions another pig foot specimen with similar deformity, specimen number 297A; glad corr. will collect similar cases. 1
    1. See preceding letter, above. This letter may be to Otto Zacharias, and not to CD, but there is no indication of such on original.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), 1877 May 23d.; 513; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Thank [Charles] Grant [Blairfindie] Allen for having sent his book [ Physiological Aesthetics (London: H. S. King, 1877)]; thanks for letter; "good Heavens what a lot of books there is to read"; had not heard of "rub"--presumably over spontaneous generation--at Royal Society; 1 [Thomas Henry] Huxley said [John] Tyndall's work about old germs withstanding boiling was decisive; 2 would like to see question settled; Frank's [i.e. Francis Darwin's] paper on teazle has been rejected, to CD's chagrin; 3 none of sons can attend corr.'s lecture; 4 corr.'s negative results concerning spiritualism please CD, who thinks Williams [the spiritualist] is "a very clever rogue".
    1. See Glenn Vandervliet, Microbiology and the Spontaneous Generation Debate during the 1870's (Lawrence, Kansas: Coronado Press, 1971).
    2. See Tyndall, "Further Researches on the Deportment and Vital Resistance of Putrefactive and Infective Organisms...," Proc. R. Soc., 26 (1877): 228-38; and idem, "Further Researches on the Deportment and Vital Persistence of Putrefactive and Infective Organisms...," Phil. Trans. R. Soc., 167 (1877): 149-206.
    3. See Francis Darwin, "On the Protrusion of Protoplasmic Filaments from the Glandular Hairs of the Common Teasel ( Dipsacus sylvestris)," Q. Jl microsc. Sci., 17 (1877): 169-74 and 245-72. 4. Romanes, "Evolution of Nerves and Nervo-Systems," Not. Proc. Meet. Memb. R. Instn, 8 (1875-1878): 427-48.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877]; 514; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Thanks for letter; does not know what referees said about Frank's [i.e. Francis Darwin's] paper; 1 [Edwin] Ray Lankester and [John Hutton] Balfour have seen [teasel] filaments; latter is sure they are protoplasm; "It is terribly discouraging to a young worker to have his work rejected because the facts are quite new"; 1 will show corr.'s letter to Frank; will read corr.'s lecture when it appears in Nature; 2 deception during seances is wicked and scandalous; will take a month's rest soon [from June 8 to July 4, 1877]; 3 has read a third of [Charles] Grant [Blairfindie] Allen's book, finding it clever but too "deductive"; Allen neglects effects of habit. 1
    2. "Evolution of Nerves and Nervo-Systems," Nature, Lond., 16 (1877): 231-33, 269-71, and 289-93.
    3. See "Darwin's Journal," 20.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), 1877 June 5.; 515; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Thought corr. would like the following extract, found by chance, and bearing on effects of habit in passage of nervous force. 1
    1. See Jean Lamarck, Philosophie Zoologique, 2v. (Paris: Baillière, 1830), II, 318, paragraph beginning: "Dans toute action, le fluide...."
  - To [George John] ROMANES; "My address will be/ `Bassett, Southampton.' " 1, [1877] June 11th.; 516; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: More Letters, I, 367-68 (letter 279). p. 367, line 7, change "purchases" to "preserves".
    1. Down address variant, type 8, is crossed out. Also crossed out is "Leith Hill Place".
  - To [Rudolf August Birminghold LUDWIG] 1; Down (type 8), [1877 July 16th]; 517; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Received letter and essay dedicated to CD, dated July 4, only today; 2 it is interesting to discover in ancient forms any characters now present in distinct species or subgroups, and Crocodilus Darwinii is excellent illustration of this.
    1. Pencil note on third page reads: "addressed Herrn Rudolphe Ludwig/ Waldstrasse 49/ Darmstadt/ July 16th 1877".
    2. See Rudolf Ludwig, Fossile Crocodiliden aus der Tertiärformation des Mainzer Beckens... (Cassell, 1877).
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877] Augt. 9th; 518; ALS; 8 x5; 6p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: Life of Romanes, 56-57. p. 57, line 4, change "half of the botanists" to "half-a-score of Botanists". Also printed, with changes: More Letters, II, 406-07 (letter 731).
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877] Aug. 10th; 519; ALS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: Life of Romanes, 62-63. Printed, with minor changes and minor omissions: More Letters, II, 407-08 (letter 733). p. 407, line 1, change "went" to "wrote".
  - From Léo ERRERA; Venise., 1877 Sept. 15; 520; Draft of ALS; 8 x5.5 3p. (in French) 1
    Has studied heterostylism for some years in the Primula elatior; has prepared manuscript on subject with G[ustave] Gevaert, in which there is a correction of a point made in Darwin, Cross and Self Fertilisation (1876); wishes to send portion of manuscript that deals with CD's book to CD for review; reply in English.
  - To Léo [Abram] ERRERA; Down (type 8), 1877 Sep 18. [pmk. SP18/ 77]; 521; LS; 8 x5; 2p. and env., add. [Mons: Léo Errera/ 6A. Rue Royale 6A/ Brussels/ Belgium]
    Would be happy to look at corr.'s MS.; to save CD's time, mark pages which CD should scan; will read paper in entirety when published; 1 has recently published Different Forms of Flowers [(1877)], in which results of some experiments on P. elatior are given. 2
    1. See Errera and Gevaert, "Sur la Structure et les Modes de Fecondation des Fleurs et en Particulier sur l'Hétérostylie du Primula elatior," Belg. Soc. Bot. Bull., 17 (1878): 38-181 and 182-248.
    2. See preceding letter, above.
  - From L[éo Abram] E[RRERA]; Bruxelles/ 6A rue royale. IN TWO PARTS IN VAULT, EACH HAVING SEPARATE FOLDER. PART II NOT FILMED, 1877 Sept. 30; 522; Draft of ALS; various sizes; 3p. (in French) 1
    Thanks for prompt letter; has marked the essential passages of the MS. for CD's comment in blue crayon; have borrowed from [A. von Marilaun] Kerner the terms "autogamy", "geitonogamy", "xenogamy", and "allogamy"; discusses the advantages of these; points out the main elements of the argument in the MS.; thanks CD for copy of Darwin, Different Forms of Flowers [(1877)]; mentions terminology used by Herman Müller and [F.] Delpino. 1
    1. Free translation into English provided by editor's wife, Nancy E. Carroll. See preceding letter, above.
  - To Léo [Abram] ERRERA; Down (type 8) (last two lines crossed out), 1877 Oct 4th [pmk. OC4/ 77]; 523; LS; 8 x5; 4p. and env., add. [Monsieur Léo Errera/ 6A Rue Royale/ Brussells]
    Printed in full, with minor changes: More Letters, II, 413-14 (letter 741).
  - From L[éo Abram] E[RRERA]; no location, 1877. Oct 10; 524; Draft of ALS; 8.5 x6.5 2p. (in French) 1
    Thanks for aid; has already begun work upon inconspicuous flowers; explains why he concluded that CD believed that autogamy generally was more advantageous than geitonogamy. 1
    1. Translation into English provided by editor's wife, Nancy E. Carroll. See also preceding four letters, above.
  - To?; Down (type 8), 1877 Oct 15.; 525; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Thanks for curious photographs; will read account of them with interest; appearance of same abnormality in different races of humans in different environments has always seemed remarkable to CD; did not know corr.'s pupil R[udolf] von Willemoes-Suhm, but had read his papers, esp. on development of cirripedes; had "highest opinion of his abilities. His death has been a very serious loss to natural science."
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877 December 1-2]; 526; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: Life of Romanes, 66-67. Printed, with minor changes and minor omissions: More Letters, I, 370-71 (letter 281).
    1. Date determined from date of Romanes's reply; see Life of Romanes, 68-69.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), 1877 Dec 5.; 527; LS; 18 x5; 3p.
    CD's gardener does not know what onion worm is; onions can be planted at Down in part of garden where onions have not grown for 30 years; will take charge of experimental plants for corr.; thanks for letter; Romanes overestimates CD and his works; it would be absurd for CD to suddenly be called "Dr".
    1. Francis Darwin, CD's amanuensis, penned a short note at end of letter, recommending that Romanes try "Thymol" upon his medusas.
  - To?; Down (type 8), 1877 Dec. 11; 528; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    Thanks for letter; would like to see six letters of grandfather [Erasmus Darwin] published, but grandfather's name and that of [Johann Albrecht Heinrich] Reimarus are so unknown that no editor would want to publish the letters; would like to see letters if brought to England.
  - To R[euben A.] BLAIR; Down (type 8), 1877 Dec 27. [pmk. APR/ 27]; 529; LS; 8 x5; 2p. and env., add. [R. Blair Esq/ Sedalia/ Missouri/ U.S.A.]
    Thanks for news of the case of the goose; seems to show inheritance of the effects of injury; such cases are rare and should be examined; send wing to CD, if possible; see if goose had normal offspring before injury.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1877-1878]; 530; ALS; 8 x5; 6p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: Life of Romanes, 105-07.
    1. CD mentions "perforation of the corolla by bees" in this letter as being on page 425 of Darwin, Cross and Self Fertilisation. This only occurred in the first edition, published November 10, 1876; see Freeman, page 31. Therefore, 1877 is lower endpoint. A new, second edition appeared in 1878 without any mention of perforation on page 425; this sets upper endpoint for letter.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), 1878 March 7.; 531; LS; 8 x5; 2p.
    CD's gardener says onions sown before middle of March may be injured by frost, but if CD delays in planting, onions will not be ready by May; should CD take risk and plant now; is glad corr.'s essay will appear in the Fortnightly; was thinking about it the other day; books were sent by rail in morning. 1
    1. See Romanes, "The Scientific Evidence of Organic Evolution: A Discourse," Fortnightly Rev., 30 (1881): 739-58.
  - To?; Down (type 8), 1878 March 28th; 532; ALS; 8 x5; 1p.
    Thanks for letter; temperament or mental disposition depends on structure of the brain, so nature of milk digested probably does not affect character of child; case of diseases is different; facts about starling imitating cries and songs of other birds are curious, but "I have become so absorbed with vegetable physiology that it is not likely I shall ever again attend to the minds of the higher animals."
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1878] April 9th; 533; ALS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Condolences [on loss of sister]; 1 leaves home on 27th and returns on May 13; invites corr. to Down before or after these dates; onions are not yet up; doubts that corr. could do anything with onions before leaving for Scotland. 2
    1. See Life of Romanes, 69-71.
    2. On onions, see also letter to Romanes, March 7, 1878, above.
  - From W[illiam] H[enry] FLOWER; Royal College of Surgeons of England/ Lincoln's Inn Fields/ (W.C.), 1878 April 12; 534; ALS; 8 x5; 4p.
    Was delayed in looking at goose's wing; sketches the wing's bones on the back of [Reuben A.] Blair's letter; bones are normal, but appear to have been abnormally flexed; proposes "far-fetched" hypothesis in which such an injury might have led to "some disturbance in the functons of the nerves which control the muscles of the same region" in the offspring; must examine several wings, especially of very young birds, to check this; wing of original goose should be examined as well; case is worth following up. 1
    1. See also letter to Blair, December 27, 1877, above. With this letter is a copy of same, plus an env., add. to "R. A. Blair Esq/ Sedalia/ Missouri/ U.S.A" and pmk. "Beckenham/ DE27/ 77". It should accompany earlier letter, of course.
  - To [Reuben A. BLAIR]; Down (type 8), 1878 Ap. 14.; 535; LS; 8 x5; 4p. and photo of goose (enclosure wanting) 1
    Thanks for wing of goose, photograph, and letter; enclosed explains delay of [William Henry] Flower; send wings requested by Flower directly to Flower; CD will pay expenses for this undertaking; return letters to CD; did old gander bleed when it was wounded; did wound suppurate; did wing heal quickly or slowly; these questions relate to inheritance of mutilations.
    Include photo of gosling with turned with features
    1. Enclosure is obviously Flower's report, which is abstracted above as a letter to CD.
  - To Rob[er]t THOMSON; no location [Envelope add. to Thomson, but note does not belong with the envelope], [1878 May 23] [end. 1878; pmk. MY23/ 78]; 536; ALS; 4.5 x7 3/4; 1p. and env., add. [Robt Thomson Esq/ Beaufort/ South Carolina/ U.S.A.], end. [Charly Darwin/ 1878]
    Orders "large pot of soft spermaceti ointment".
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1878]; 537; LS; 8 x5; 4p. (enclosures wanting)
    Wrote notes on insects 40 years ago and used them in long chapter on instinct written four or five years before Darwin, Origin [(1859)]; sends two pages of this chapter; offers entire chapter of 110 pages for Romanes's use, but presumes it is too late to be of any good; Frank [i.e. Francis Darwin] took the baby [i.e. Bernard Richard Meirion Darwin] to see train and called engine a "puff puff"; baby now calls all vehicles and chimneys and fires (lighted or unlighted) by the name "boo boo"; more onions from last lot have died, apparently because of wet weather, but total deaths are few; 1 one pea has sent up an aborted shoot of a half plumule.
    1. See letter to Romanes, April 9, 1878, above.
  - To [George John] ROMANES; Down (type 8), [1878] June 19th; 538; ALS; 8 x5; 3p.
    Printed in full, with minor changes: Life of Romanes, 72.
  - To [a son of Edward TRUELOVE]; Down (type 8), 1878 July 1.; 539; ALS; 8 x5; 3p. and end. [Chas. Darwin]
    Private letter; had not heard of corr.'s father until his trial; cannot sign memorial for this reason; has no reason to doubt corr.'s father's character; "I have not seen the Moral Phys. by R[obert] D[ale] Owen, but I have heard the nature of its contents; & though I am strongly opposed to all such views & plans, yet the Conviction of your Father seemed to me very harsh, as the publication of works of this nature can hardly be considered as obscene in the ordinary sense of the word." 1
    1. See: Owen, Moral Physiology; or, a Brief and Plain Treatise on the Population Question... (New York: 1831); and Edward Truelove, In the High Court of Justice. Queen's Bench Division, February 1, 1878. The Queen v. E. Truelove, for Publishing the Hon. R. D. Owen's "Moral Physiology"... (London: 1878). Copy of the latter is at British Museum.
  - To [Reuben A. BLAIR]; Down (type 9), 1878 July 4th; 540; ALS; 8 x5; 1p.
    Thanks for letter and for kindness; has written to [William Henry] Flower with all particulars and has urged Flower to examine wings carefully; there may be delay caused by holiday; corr. will receive word. 1
    1. See letter to Blair, April 14, 1878, above.